Luca Zhou

www.lucazhou.ca linkedin.com/in/lucazhou lucazhoumc@outlook.com github.com/chefZau +1 (647)893-2063

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Experience in **Object-Oriented Programming** with **Java** and **C++**.

Highly experienced in data wrangling using Pandas and Numpy.

Proficient in creating visualizations using Seaborn, and Matplotlib.

Familiar with data pipeline; capable of finishing tasks on strict deadlines.

EDUCATION

Honors Specialization in Computer Science

London, ON

University of Western Ontario

Sept. 2017 - June 2022

 $\circ~$ Dean's Honor List in the 2018 - 2019 and 2019 - 2020 academic year

Data Analyst Nanodegree

Udacity, Inc. Feb. 2021

Data Scientist with Python Track (23 Courses)

Data Camp, Inc. Oct. 2021

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst London, ON

LBM Partner Services Inc.

Sept. 2020 - Sept. 2021

- Data Collection: Used Python and SQL to acquire data from various sources, including APIs, Web and etc.
- Data Cleaning: Filtered and cleaned data using Pandas and Numpy to locate and correct problems. Typical tasks including finding text similarity, handling missing values, dropping duplicates and aligning data types.
- Data Visualization: Created visualizations and dynamic BisTrack dashboards using Seaborn, and SQL to tell 'data stories' that are clear and easy to understand to provide clients with specific, actionable recommendations.
- Database Normalization: Built the industry database by normalizing a 10-million row table.
- **Python Automation**: Created Python automations to suit client needs, including a route optimization app for deliveries, HubSpot integration, and a server monitoring project.

Back-end Developer Intern

Guangzhou, China

TRS Information Technology Co.

July 2019 - Aug. 2019

- o Data Platform: Participated in a team of 16 people to develop a data platform using Spring Boot and Vue.js.
- Web Scraping: Wrote Python scrapers for data collection on more than ten websites including macroeconomic, meteorological, national and industry statistics. Typical libraries used: Request, BeautifulSoup, and Selenium
- Database Design: Coordinated with the requirements department to design, implement, operate MySQL.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C++, C, VBA, SQL

Data Science Toolbox: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, PowerBI

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Node.js, Express, Flask, RESTful APIs, GraphQL

Tools: SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, Git

PROJECTS

To Do List Web: Developed a minimal, clean, and responsive static website using HTML, CSS, and jQuery for planning, managing, and tracking all day to day activities.

Simulated Medical System: Built a simulated web-based medical system written using LAMP Stack. It allows end-users to perform CURD operations to a database through the website.